Alright in this video we're gonna go deep into mathematical logic and set
theory to try and figure out what Math is. Right off the bat,
because of Godel's incompleteness theorems, there is no clear cut answer to this,
but one possible answer is that math is the theory of ZFC.
Which is just the set of all first
order consequences of these axioms right here.
We'll try and figure out what that means right now.
To keep things simple, we can imagine
a black box theorem proving computer.
In a later video we will open the hood of this
black box computer, but for this video, just see it as
some computer which takes in sentences written in first order logic,
and it outputs the logical consequences of these sentences.
The ultimate goal, is to find some set of axioms which
we could feed into our theorem prover such that it outputs
every true mathematical statement, without ever outputting a false statement.
Again, this is impossible due to this guy,
so the best we can hope for is some set of
axioms which can output pretty much all of math. So then
the question is, what axioms should we feed in?